Finding Aid for Sally Fleming papers, 1928-1988
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Sally Fleming papers 1928-1988
Fleming, Sally.
3 linear feet
2009086 Aa 2
Wife of the President of the University of Michigan; correspondence, organizational files, appointment books, diaries, speeches, and other personal materials.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The Sally Fleming papers (donor no. 5769 ) came to the library as part of the Robben Fleming collection in 1979. Periodic additions have been received since 1979.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Sally Fleming was wife of Robben Fleming, president of the University of Michigan. In this capacity, she played an active role on the Ann Arbor campus, hosting innumerable teas, luncheons, and dinners for university-related groups. Sally Fleming was also involved in various social and cultural organizations, including the Ann Arbor Child Care and Development Center, the Right to Read organization, Youth for Understanding, and the Washtenaw County League for Planned Parenthood.
The Sally Fleming collection includes correspondence, speeches and notes, an article written in 1974 on the history of music in Ann Arbor, appointment books, clippings, and topical files relating to her organizational activities. Her papers, together with those of her husband, provide a valuable record of the social demands made upon the presidential family. Moreover, Sally Fleming became directly involved in a number of organizations concerned with child care, music, and other cultural and social concerns in each of the communities in which she lived. Many of the topical files contained in this series reflect this concern and activity.
Subjects:
Fleming, R. W. (Robben Wright), 1916-2010.; Fleming, Sally.; University of Michigan. President.
- Correspondence
  - General correspondence
    - Undated (Box 1)
    - Undated (Thank you notes) (Box 1)
    - 1936-1955 (Box 1)
    - 1960-December 1978, 13 folders (Box 1)
    - April-May 1988, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Letters from Robben Fleming
    - July-August, 1950, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - January, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Thank you letters and notes received (Box 1)
- Speeches and writings
  - Speeches, transcripts and notes circa 1967-1978 (Box 1)
  - Drafts of speeches and speech materials, 1 volumes (Box 1)
  - Article, "Music in Ann Arbor, 1824-1974" and notes 1974 (Box 1)
  - Poetry (Box 1)
- Personal Records
  - School materials circa 1929-1937 (Box 1)
  - Junior High School Yearbooks 1928-1931, 3 volumes (Box 1)
  - Beloit College circa 1938-1939 (notes and miscellanea) (Box 1)
  - Music programs circa 1934-1972 (Box 1)
  - Church activities circa 1961-1963 (notes) (Box 1)
  - Entertainment notes 1964-1966 (Box 1)
  - Diary January-October 1971 (Box 2)
  - Trip to China 1976 (travel diary, notes and miscellanea), 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Miscellanea, 2 folders (Box 2)
- Organizational Activities
  - The Alumni Association of the University of Michigan, Athena Awards 1973 (correspondence and related material) (Box 2)
  - Ann Arbor Child Care and Development Center
    - Correspondence, minutes and memoranda 1971-1974 (Box 2)
    - Miscellanea 1970-1974 (Box 2)
  - Ann Arbor Child Care
    - Notes circa 1969-1975 (Box 2)
    - Miscellanea circa 1972-1973 (Box 2)
  - Ann Arbor School Volunteer Program 1969-1970 (manual and minutes) (Box 2)
  - Association of American Universities 1974, 1977-1978 (correspondence, memoranda, agendas, and itineraries) (Box 2)
  - Champaign County [Ill.] Urban League
    - Records 1963-1964 (notes and clippings), 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Dane County [Wis.] Citizens Association for Children and Youth
    - Notes and correspondence 1966 (Box 2)
    - Notes circa 1966-1967 (Box 2)
    - Miscellanea, including source materials circa 1966 (Box 2)
  - First United Presbyterian Church, Urbana, Ill.
    - Correspondence 1958-1964 (Box 2)
    - Scrapbook and miscellanea (Box 2)
  - Leigh Roberts Rehabilitation House, Madison, Wis. 1966 (source material and notes) (Box 2)
  - Michigan Literacy, Inc. 1977 (source materials) (Box 2)
  - Mozart Club, Champaign-Urbana, Ill.
    - Scrapbook 1959-1960 (Box 2)
    - Programs, clippings, and miscellanea 1944-1964 (Box 2)
  - Right to Read 1974-1975
    - Correspondence, minutes, notes (Box 2)
    - Program materials and miscellaneous newsletters (Box 2)
  - Teaching-Learning Communities 1978, 1976 (correspondence and source materials) (Box 2)
  - The University of Michigan, Center for Continuing Education for Women
    - Correspondence and source materials circa 1974-1978, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Washtenaw County League for Planned Parenthood
    - Board minutes and related material 1978 (Box 2)
    - Education Committee minutes and related material 1978 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, notes, and source materials 1977-1978 (Box 2)
  - Washtenaw United Way 1974 (correspondence and source materials) (Box 2)
  - YWCA 1967-1968, 1978 (notes and source materials) (Box 2)
  - Youth for Understanding
    - Transcript of board meeting May 23, 1974 (including clippings, and miscellaneous materials 1973-1974) (Box 2)
    - Correspondence and source materials (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous
  - Presidential spouses questionnaire (Box 2)
  - School of Music Master Class Series (Box 2)
  - Publications and other miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Clippings 1930-1979, 4 folders (Box 2)
- Daily Appointment Books
  - 1963-1978, 20 volumes (Box 2)
Related Material
The library has a separate collection of personal papers of Robben W. Fleming as well as the records of the office of the President of the University of Michigan during the time of his presidency.